<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>
<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
      file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">

<task type="function" name="feather">
	<shortdescription>Combine two images using their Fourier transforms</shortdescription>
	<description>
The algorithm converts each image to the gridded visibility
plane, combines them, and reconverts them into an combined
image.  The images must have a well-defined beam shape (clean beam),
given in the image, in order for feathering to work well.
The two images must be on the same grid and have the same
flux density normalization scale.

	</description>
	<input>
		<param type="string" name="imagename">
			<description>Name of output feathered image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="string" name="highres" mustexist="true">
			<description>Name of high resolution (interferometer) image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="string" name="lowres" mustexist="true">
			<description>Name of low resolution (single dish) image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
	</input>

<example>
	This algorithm transforms each image to the gridded visibility plane,
	combines them, and retransforms them into an combined image.
	"Feathering" is usually used as a way to combine different data sets
	that each cover different spatial frequency ranges, i.e. single dish
	and interferometer data.  It gets its name from smoothly switching from
	one data set to the other using weights assigned according to the
	sensitivity of each at any given spatial frequency.  Note that it does
	not fill in gaps, if any, between the spatial frequency ranges.

	Each image must include a well-defined beam shape (clean beam)
	for feathering to work well.  The two images must be on the same grid and
	have the same flux density normalization scale.

	Keyword arguments:
        imagename -- Name of output feathered image
                default: none; example: imagename='orion_combined.im'
        highres -- Name of high resolution (interferometer) image
                default: none; example: highres='orion_vla.im'
	     This image is often a clean image obtained from synthesis
		observations.
        lowres -- Name of low resolution (single dish) image
                default: none; example: lowres='orion_gbt.im'
	     This image is often a image from a single-dish observations
	        or a clean image obtained from lower resolution synthesis
		observations.
</example>
</task>
</casaxml>
