<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>
<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
      file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">

<task type="function" name="feather">
	<shortdescription>Combine two images using their Fourier transforms</shortdescription>
	<description>
The algorithm converts each image to the gridded visibility
plane, combines them, and reconverts them into an combined
image.  The images must have a well-defined beam shape (clean beam),
given in the image, in order for feathering to work well.
The two images must be on the same grid and have the same
flux density normalization scale.

	</description>
	<input>
		<param type="string" name="imagename">
			<description>Name of output feathered image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="string" name="highres" mustexist="true">
			<description>Name of high resolution (interferometer) image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="string" name="lowres" mustexist="true">
			<description>Name of low resolution (single dish) image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
	</input>

<example>

	This algorithm, called feathering, is a simple method for combining two
        images with different spatial resolution.  The processing steps are:

               1. transform each image to the gridded visibility plane,
               2. sum the gridded visibilities
               3. trasnform back to the image plane.

        The task name comes from the  smooth switching from
	one data set to the other using weights assigned according to the
	sensitivity of each at any given spatial frequency.  Gaps, if any,
        between the spatial frequency ranges are not filled.

	Each image have a well-defined beam shape (clean beam)
	for feathering to work well.  The two images must be on the same grid and
	have the same flux density normalization scale.

        This task is somewhat experimental and will improve as more experience
        with single-dish and interferometric data are obtained over the next few years.


	Keyword arguments:
        imagename -- Name of output feathered image
                default: none; example: imagename='orion_combined.im'
        highres -- Name of high resolution (interferometer) image
                default: none; example: highres='orion_vla.im'
	     This image is often a clean image obtained from synthesis
		observations.
        lowres -- Name of low resolution (single dish) image
                default: none; example: lowres='orion_gbt.im'
	     This image is often a image from a single-dish observations
	        or a clean image obtained from lower resolution synthesis
		observations.

        Comments:

            The advantage of feathering is that one does not have to go back to the
            visibility data and then image and deconvolve.  It starts with the
            high-quality image (with the accurate clean beam).  This is particularly
            useful for combining a high-resolution interferometric image with a
            lower-resolution single-dish image, although D-configuration and A-configuration
            EVLA data can also be combined.   There are often uncertainties in the
            relative flux density scales between the two images, and the current
            implementation of feathers does not adjustment.

            The clean task also has a method of combining two sets of data with different
            resolution.  The high resolution visibility data begins deconvolution, starting
            with a modelimage of the lower-resolution image.  The lower-resolution image must
            be clean components (or a sky model), not the low resolution image with its
            intrinsic resolution.

</example>
</task>
</casaxml>
