<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>
<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">


<!-- This is the param set for sdlist -->

<task type="function" name="sdlist" startup="false" category="single dish">

  <shortdescription>ASAP SD task: list summary of single dish data</shortdescription>

  <description>
        ASAP SD listing task: list summary of the single dish data

        Modified 2008-02-01 TT
        Task Version 2007-03-04 STM
</description>

  <input>

    <param type="string" name="sdfile"  mustexist="true">

    <description>name of input SD dataset</description>
    <value></value>
    </param>

    <param type="any" name="antenna">
            <description>antenna name or id (only effective for MS input)</description>
            <any type="variant" limittype="string int"/>
            <value type="int">0</value>
    </param> 

    <param type="bool" name="scanaverage">
            <description>average integs within scans (True,False) </description>
            <value>False</value>
    </param>

    <param type="string" name="listfile">
	    <description>Name of output file for summary list</description>
	    <value></value>
    </param>

    <param type="bool" name="overwrite">
            <description>overwrite the output file if already exists</description>
            <value>False</value>
    </param>

    </input>

  <returns type="void"/>

  <example>
        Keyword arguments:
        sdfile -- name of input SD dataset
        antenna -- antenna name or id (only effective for MS input). 
        scanaverage -- average integrations within scans
                options: (bool) True,False
                default: False
                example: if True, this happens in read-in
                         For GBT, set False!
        listfile -- Name of output file for summary list
                default: '' (no output file)
                example: 'mysd_summary.txt'
        overwrite -- overwrite the output file if already exists
                options: (bool) True,False
                default: False


        DESCRIPTION:

        Task sdlist lists the scan summary of the dataset after importing
        as a scantable into ASAP.  It will optionally output this summary
        as file.

        Note that if your PAGER environment variable is set to 'less' and
        you have set the 'verbose' ASAP environment variable to True
        (the default), then the screen version of the summary will page.
        You can disable this for sdlist by setting
        sd.rcParams['verbose']=False
        before running sdlist.  Set it back afterwards if you want lots
        of information.

        WARNING for the GBT raw SDFITS format data as input:
        Currently, all SDtasks cannot handle GBT raw SDFITS format data
        (in which the data are stored in multiple tables within SDFITS).
        It may be still possible to reduce GBT data after some
        preprocessing (outside CASA) of the raw SDFITS to a SDFITS with
        a single data table or to other data formats handled by SDtasks.


  </example>

</task>

</casaxml>
