<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>

<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">


<!-- This is the task interface for imcollapse        -->
<!--                                                          -->

<task type="function" name="imcollapse" category="analysis">

<shortdescription>Collapse image along one axis, aggregating pixel values along that axis.</shortdescription>

<input>
    <param type="string" name="imagename" mustexist="true">
    	<description>Name of the input image</description>
    	<value/>
        <example>imagenam='ngc5921.im'</example>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="function">
        <description>Function used to compute aggregation of pixel values.</description>
        <value/>
        <example>function="max"</example>
        <example>function="rms</example>
        <example>function="mean"</example>
    </param>
    <param type="variant" name="axes">
        <description>Zero-based axis number(s) or minimal match strings to collapse.</description>
        <value>[0]</value>
        <example>axis=2</example>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="outfile">
        <description>Name of output CASA image. Must be specified.</description>
        <value/>
        <example>outfile='collapsed.im'</example>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="box">
        <description>Optional direction plane box ("blcx, blcy, trcx trcy").</description>
        <value/>
        <example>box="100,100,200,200"</example>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="region" subparam="true">
        <description>Region specification. See help par.region. Default is to not use a region.</description>
        <value/>
        <example>region="my.rgn"</example>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="chans">
        <description>Optional zero-based contiguous frequency channel specification. See "help par.chans" for examples.</description>
        <value/>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="stokes">
        <description>Optional contiguous stokes planes specification.</description>
        <value/>
        <example>stokes="iq"</example>
    </param>
    <param type="string" name="mask">
        <description>Mask to use. See help par.mask. Default is none.</description>
        <value type="string"/>
    </param>
    <param type="bool" name="overwrite" subparam="true">
        <description>Overwrite exisitng ouput file if it exists?</description>
        <value>False</value>
        <example>overwrite=true</example>
    </param>
    <param type="bool" direction="in" name="stretch">
        <description>Stretch the mask if necessary and possible? See help par.stretch </description>
        <value>False</value>
    </param>
    
    <constraints>
        <when param="outfile">
            <notequals type="string" value="">
                <default param="overwrite">
                    <value>False</value>
                </default>
            </notequals>
        </when>
        <when param="box">
            <equals type="string" value="">
                <default param="region">
                    <value>""</value>
                </default>
            </equals>
        </when>
        <when param="mask">
            <notequals type="string" value="">
                <default param="stretch">
                    <value>False</value>
                </default>
            </notequals>
        </when>
    </constraints>
</input>
<returns type="bool"/>

<example>
PARAMETER SUMMARY
imagename        Name of the input (CASA, FITS, MIRIAD) image
function         Function used to compute aggregation of pixel values along the collapsed
                 axis. Supported functions are max, mean, median, min, rms, stdev,
                 sum, variance. Minimum match is supported for the function parameter (eg,
                 function="r" will compute the rms of the pixel values).
axis             Zero-based axis number(s) or minimal match strings to compress.
outfile          Name of output CASA image. Must be specified.
overwrite        Controls if an already existing file by the
                 same name can be overwritten. If true, the user is not prompted, the file
                 if it exists is automatically overwritten.
box              Direction plane box specification, "blcx, blcy, trcx, trcy". Only one box
                 may be specified. If not specified, region is used if specified. If region
                 is also not specified, entire directional plane unioned with any chans and
                 stokes specification determines the region.
region           Region specification. See help par.region. Default is to not use a region.
chans            Optional contiguous frequency channel number specification. Not used if
                 region is specified. Default is all channels. See "help par.chans" for examples.
stokes           Contiguous stokes planes specification. Not used if region is specified.
                 Default is all stokes.
mask             Mask to use. See help par.mask. Default is none.
stretch          Stretch the input mask if necessary and possible. Only used if a mask is specified.
                 See help par.stretch.

This task collapses an image along a specified axis or set of axes of N pixels to a single pixel on each
specified axis. It computes the specified aggregate function for pixel values along the specified axes
and places those values in the single remaining plane of those axes in the output image. It returns
an image analysis tool containing the newly created collapsed image if wantreturn=True. Choices of
aggregate functions are: max, mean, median, min, rms, stdev, sum, variance. Minimal unique match is
supported for the function parameter (eg, function="r" will compute the rms of the pixel values, "med"
will compute the median).
        
Axes can be specified as a single integer or array of integers indicating the zero-based axes along
which to collapse the image. Axes may also be specified as a single or array of strings which minimally
and uniquely match (ignoring case) world axes names in the image (eg "dec" or ["ri, "d"] for
collapsing along the declination axis or along the right ascension and declination axes, respectively).
         
The reference pixel of the collapsed axis is set to 0 and its reference value is set to the mean
of the the first and last values of that axis in the specified region of the input image.

# myimage.im is a 512x512x128x4 (ra,dec,freq,stokes) image
imagename = "myimage.im"
# collapse a subimage of it along its spectral axis avoiding the 8 edge
# channels at each end of the band, computing the mean value of the pixels
# resulting image is 256x256x1x4 in size.
outfile="collapse_spec_mean.im"
function="mean"
axis=2
box="127,127,383,383"
chans="8~119"
imcollapse(imagename=imagename, outfile=outfile, function=function, axes=axis, box=box, chans=chans)

</example>

</task>

</casaxml>
