<help>
    <category name="General Use">
        <group name="Tasks">
            <item name="Requirements">
                CasaBrowser is meant to be distributed with the CASA system and
                will not work as a standalone application.  When CASA is
                installed, a Qt version of at least 4.3.0 is required.  In
                addition, the Qwt library is also required to enable plotting.
                The version of Qwt must be at least 5.0.2.
            </item><item name="Usage">
                Once CASA has been installed and built, the executable for
                CasaBrowser can be found in the [CASA]/[architecture]/bin/
                directory (for example: /casa/linux_gnu/bin).  Since this
                directory is placed on the path, the executable should be
                runnable from any location.<br /><br />
                CasaBrowser can be run in two ways:<br />
                <ul><li><code>casabrowser</code><br />
                When run with no arguments, a CasaBrowser window will open without
                any tables.  The menubar can be then be used to open table(s) as
                desired.<br /></li>
                <li><code>casabrowser path/to/table</code><br />
                When run with one or more arguments, a CasaBrowser window will
                open and display each of the provided tables (provided that they
                are valid).</li></ul><h3> </h3><br />
                CasaBrowser is also accessible from within casapy by using the
                browsetable() command.
            </item>
        </group>
        <group name="Information">
            <item name="CASA Table Data Types">
                The following datatypes are supported by the table browser:
                <ul><li>Float</li>
                    <li>Float Array</li>
                    <li>Double<br />Date: a special type of Double</li>
                    <li>Double Array</li>
                    <li>Integer</li>
                    <li>Integer Array</li>
                    <li>Unsigned Integer</li>
                    <li>Unsigned Integer Array</li>
                    <li>Short Integer</li>
                    <li>Short Integer Array</li>
                    <li>Complex</li>
                    <li>Complex Array</li>
                    <li>DComplex</li>
                    <li>DComplex Array</li>
                    <li>Boolean</li>
                    <li>Boolean Array</li>
                    <li>String</li>
                    <li>String Array</li>
                    <li>Unsigned Character</li>
                    <li>Unsigned Character Array</li>
                    <li>Character</li>
                    <li>Character Array</li>
                    <li>Table</li>
                    <li>Record</li></ul><h3> </h3><br />
                The following CASA data types are not supported by the table
                browser:
                <ul><li>Unsigned Short Integer</li>
                    <li>Unsigned Short Integer Array</li>
                    <li>Other</li></ul><h3> </h3><br />
                For more information see the CASA table documentation.
            </item><item name="Useful Links">
                <ul><li>CASA Homepage: http://casa.nrao.edu</li>
                    <li>CASA Table Documentation:
                        http://aips2.nrao.edu/docs/tables/implement/Tables.html
                        </li>
                    <li>TaQL Documentation:
                         http://aips2.nrao.edu/docs/notes/199/199.html</li>
                </ul><h3> </h3>
            </item>
        </group>
    </category>
    <category name="Browsing">
        <group name="Tasks">
            <item name="Open Table(s)">
                There are two ways to open a CASA table: on the command-line or
                through a file chooser dialog.<br />
                <ul><li><b>Command-line</b>: See <a href="general_use.html#tasks1">Usage</a>.<br /> </li>
                <li><b>File Chooser</b>: Once a CasaBrowser window has been opened,
                files can be opened by selecting the <b>File - Open Table</b> menu
                option or by using the <b>Ctrl+O</b> keyboard shortcut.<br />
                <img src="images/1-opentable.png" /></li></ul><h3> </h3><br />
                If opening the table succeeded, the table should appear in a new
                tab.  If opening failed, an error message will appear with details
                on the failure.
            </item><item name="Open Table(s) with TaQL">
                To open a table with TaQL (see <a href="general_use.html#information1">links</a>
                for documentation), use the <b>File - Open TaQL (Ctrl+Shift+O)</b>
                command.  You will be presented with a dialog to enter your
                TaQL command.  There is a rudimentary TaQL command builder, but
                currently it is somewhat primitive and only supports the
                SELECT command.  If using the builder, be sure to click the
                "Generate" button to generate the TaQL command before clicking
                "Accept".
                
                <br /><br /><img src="images/23-taql.png" />
            </item><item name="Close Table(s)">
                There are three ways to close a table: <b>File - Close Table
                (Ctrl+W)</b>, which closes the currently selected table; <b>File -
                Close...</b>, which allows you to choose which of the opened
                tables you wish to close; and <b>File - Close All</b>, which
                closes all opened tables.<br />
                <img src="images/2-closetable.png" />
            </item><item name="Saved Views">
                When you close a CasaBrowser window, the default behavior is to save the
                currently opened "view."  A view consists of:
                <ul><li>The last directory you opened a table from,</li>
                    <li>A list of currently opened tables,</li>
                    <li>Which table was currently selected.</li>
                    <li>For each opened table:
                        <ul><li>Which columns (if any) were hidden,</li>
                            <li>Where each column was moved to (if they were moved),</li>
                            <li>Which rows were loaded,</li>
                            <li>The current row filter, if there was one,</li>
                            <li>The field formats, if there were any,</li>
                            <li>The current sort order (if any) of the fields.</li></ul>
                    </li></ul><h3> </h3>
                If you do not wish the view to be saved, this may be turned off in the
                Options (see Browsing:Edit Options).
            </item><item name="Edit Options">
                Options for the CasaBrowser can be edited with the <b>Edit - Options</b>
                command.  Currently, two options may be adjusted:
                <ul><li><b>Save View on Close</b>: indicates whether, when the CasaBrowser
                        is closed, the current view should be saved.  (See Browsing:Saved
                        Views).</li>
                    <li><b>Debug Threshold</b>: affects how much debugging output is
                        printed to the console.  Messages that have a debug level that
                        is greater than or equal to the threshold are printed.  For
                        example, if the threshold is set to High, then only messages with
                        a High level are printed, whereas a threshold of Medium will print
                        High and Medium messages.</li></ul><h3> </h3>
                <img src="images/22-options.png" />
            </item><item name="View Table Information">
                Information about an opened table can be viewed by using the
                <b>View - Table Information (Ctrl+I)</b> menu command.  A table
                information panel will open on the right side of the currently
                selected table. Information about tables provided include:<br />
                <ul><li>Location on disk</li>
                    <li>Total number of rows</li>
                    <li>Whether the table allows for insertion and/or deletion of
                        rows</li>
                    <li>List and description of fields:
                        <ul><li>Field name</li>
                            <li>Field type</li>
                            <li>Field unit (if given)</li>
                            <li>Field UCD (if given)</li>
                            <li>Field ref (if given)</li>
                            <li>Field precision (if given)</li>
                            <li>Field width (if given)</li></ul></li></ul><h3> </h3><br />
                The side panel can be closed with the "Close" button.<br />
                <img src="images/3-tableinfo.png" />
            </item><item name="View Table Data">
                Each opened table has three tabs associated with it; the first and
                topmost of these tabs is the data tab.  The data tab has two
                primary components: the data table and page navigation.
                <ul><li><b>Data Table</b>: a spreadsheet-like interface for viewing
                table data.  The column headers consist of the table fields, and
                the row headers indicate which rows of the table are currently
                being viewed.<br /><br />
                Clicking on a cell will highlight the cell, its row, and its
                column.  Double-clicking on a cell, for most data types, will
                enter into editing mode (see <a href="editing.html">Editing</a>);
                some data types, however, have special behavior for
                double-clicking:
                <ul><li><i>Arrays</i>: Text displayed in the data cell for an
                        array will either be a (potentially abbreviated) view of
                        the array itself in the case of a one-dimensional array,
                        or the shape of the array.  In either case,
                        double-clicking will open an array viewer in a side panel
                        on the right of the data tab.  The rows and columns in the
                        array viewer table correspond to the rows and column in
                        the underlying array.  In the case of an array having
                        dimension greater than two, a two-dimensional "slice" of
                        the array can be viewed at any given time.<br />
                        <img src="images/4-viewarray.png" /></li>
                    <li><i>Tables</i>: Double-clicking on a table will follow the
                        reference to that table and open it in a separate tab (if
                        the table exists).</li></ul><h3> </h3><br /></li>
                <li><b>Page Navigation</b>: only a set number of rows are loaded
                    from the table at one time.  Thus, conceptually, the table can
                    be seen as being separated into "pages", each page containing
                    the number of loaded rows.  At the bottom of the data tab are
                    components that allow for page navigation and control.<br />
                    <img src="images/5-pagenav.png" /></li></ul><h3> </h3>
            </item><item name="View Table Keywords">
                Each opened table has three tabs associated with it; the second and
                middle of these tabs is the table keywords tab. Each table keyword
                is displayed in a table in this component. Table keywords consist
                of the keyword name, the keyword type, and the keyword value.
                <br /><br />
                One of the most common uses of the table keywords are to show the
                table's subtables.  For these subtable keywords, the number of rows
                are also shown.  Additionally, double-clicking on any subtable
                keyword
                will open the specified table in a new tab.
            </item><item name="View Field Keywords">
                Each opened table has three tabs associated with it; the third and
                bottommost of these tabs is the field keywords tab.  Each field
                keyword is displayed in a tree in this component. Field keywords
                consist of the keyword name, the keyword type, and the keyword
                value.
            </item><item name="Follow Table References">
                Any data item that has an integer type can be used as a row
                reference into a subtable.  Right-clicking on a suitable data item
                will bring up a context menu that will allow you to follow the
                reference to any subtable defined in the table keywords.  If the
                subtable is not currently open, it will be opened; if the subtable
                is open, its tab will be selected.  The open table will then
                scroll to and highlight the row referenced by the data item.<br />
                <img src="images/6-followref.png" />
            </item><item name="Field Options">
                To view field options and information, right-click on a column
                header.  A context menu will be presented with the following
                options:
                <ul> <li>Field Information: Displays a pop-up dialog with the
                         field name and type along with any field keywords.
                </li><li>Statistics: For numerical fields, statistical
                         information can be displayed.  This includes the
                         minimum, maximum, and mean.  NOTE: the statistics
                         are only for the rows currently loaded in the browser.
                </li><li>Format Field: see <a href="#tasks14">Format Data
                         Display</a>.
                </li><li>Hide Column: see <a href="#tasks15">Show/Hide Columns</a>.
                </li></ul><h3> </h3>
            </item><item name="Filter Rows">
                The ability to filter rows based on data content is available
                through the <b>View - Filter on Fields (Ctrl+Shift+F)</b> menu
                command. (<b>Note</b>: Rows are filtered just on the display, not
                on the underlying table!)  A filter consists of a set of rules;
                each rule is a logical statement involving the values of one table
                field.  Multiple rules are logically "and"ed together to form the
                filter.<br /><br />
                For example, suppose that all rows in which the VALID column is not
                1 should be filtered out.  To do this, enter the rule: VALID is
                equal to 1 and then run the filter.  All rows that do <b>not</b>
                pass the filter rules are hidden in the view.  If the page is
                changed, the filter is applied to the newly loaded rows.
                <br /><br />
                The current filter can be cleared with the <b>View - Clear Filter
                (Ctrl+Shift+C)</b> menu command.
                <br /><img src="images/7-filter.png" />
            </item><item name="Search Rows">
                Rows can be searched for by using the <b>Edit - Find (Ctrl+F)</b>
                menu command.  A search is based on a set of rules; each rule is a
                logical statement involving the values of one table field.
                Multiple rules are logically "and"ed together to form the
                search.<br /><br />
                For example, suppose that you want to search for rows in which the
                VALID column is equal to 1.  To do this, enter the rule: VALID is
                equal  to 1 and then run the search.<br /><br />
                The first rule to match the search rule is highlighted in the data
                tab.  Running search again will open a new rule dialog.  To find
                the next row that matches the search rule, use <b>Edit - Find Next
                (F3)</b>, or to find the previous row that matches the search
                rule, use <b>Edit - Find Previous (Shift+F3)</b>.
            </item><item name="Sort Rows">
                There are two ways to sort rows by their field values.  The first
                is to click the field header in the data view, which will
                alternate between sorting on that row in ascending and descending
                order.  The header will have an arrow indicating the sort
                order.<br />
                <img src="images/17-sort1.png" /><br /><br />

                The second way is to use the <b>Tools - Sort (Ctrl+S)</b> command.
                A dialog will appear that will allow you to sort on multiple fields
                simultaneously.  The sort is performed starting with the top field
                and ending with the bottom field.  The header of the first field
                will have an arrow indicating the sort order.

                <br /><img src="images/18-sort2.png" /><br />
                <img src="images/19-sort3.png" /><br /><br />

                Note that sorting only sorts on the currently displayed items,
                not the entire table.<br /><br />
                To clear the current sort, use the <b>Clear Sort</b> button at the
                bottom of the data display.
            </item><item name="Format Data Display">
                Displayed data can be formatted according to its type.  To format
                data, use the <b>View - Format Display...</b> command and then
                choose the field to format.  Depending on the type, different
                formatting options may be displayed.  Once a desired format has
                been configured, it can be applied with the <b>Set Format</b>
                button.

                <br /><img src="images/8-format.png" /><br /><br />

                Once a format has been set, it can be cleared by once again
                invoking the <b>View - Format Display...</b> command and then
                clicking the <b>Clear Format</b> button.
            </item><item name="Show/Hide Columns">
                Any column can be shown or hidden in both the data and the keywords
                tab.  Columns can be shown or hidden in the <b>View - Columns</b>
                menu, or by right-clicking on the column header.<br />
                <img src="images/9-hidecolumn.png" />
            </item><item name="Move Columns">
                Any column in the data table can be moved to an arbitrary location
                in the table view.  <b>Note</b>: this does <b>not</b> change the
                order of the columns in underlying table on disk; it is merely a
                display change.  To restore the columns to their original order,
                click the "Restore Columns" button.
            </item>
        </group>
    </category>
    
    <category name="Editing">
        <group name="Tasks">
            <item name="Edit Data">
                In order to edit data, you must first enable the editing mode in
                the CasaBrowser.  (This is to prevent accidental changes.)<br />
                <img src="images/10-edittable.png" /><br /><br />

                Data can then be edited by double-clicking in the desired cell.
                Once a new value has been entered, it is checked against the data
                type to make sure the formatting is correct.  If an invalid value
                has been entered (for example, letters in a numerical field), an
                error message will be displayed and the data will revert to its
                previous value.<br /><br />

                <img src="images/11-editerror.png" /><br /><br />

                When editing array data, the array must be first opened by
                double-clicking the array so that it opens in a side-panel.
                Specific cells can then be edited by double-clicking and typing
                their new value.
            </item><item name="Save Data">
                Any changes made are immediately saved in the table on disk.
                There is therefore no need to "save" any changes made.
            </item><item name="Undo/Redo an Action">
                All edit actions are stored such that they can be undone and redone.
                The last performed action can be undone using the <b>Edit - Undo
                (Ctrl+Z)</b> command; the last undone action can be redone using the
                <b>Edit - Redo (Ctrl+Y)</b> command.<br />
                <img src="images/12-undo.png" />
            </item><item name="Insert Rows(s)">
                If the table allows it, you may insert rows with the <b>Edit - Insert
                Row(s)</b> command.  The number of rows to insert is then entered at
                the prompt.  These rows are inserted at the end of the table and may
                be edited as desired.  If you are on the last page of the table, the
                loaded rows may refresh.  Note that if your table does not allow for
                insertion of rows, this menu command will not be enabled.
                <br /><img src="images/20-insert.png" />
            </item><item name="Delete Row(s)">
                If the table allows it, you may delete rows with the <b>Edit - Delete
                Row(s)</b> command.  You then enter a comma-separated list of rows or
                row ranges that you wish to delete at the prompt.  If any of the deleted
                rows are on the page you are viewing, the loaded rows may refresh.  Note
                that if your table does not allow for the deletion of rows, this menu
                command will not be enabled.
                <br /><img src="images/21-delete.png" />
            </item>
        </group>
    </category>
    
    <category name="Plotting">
        <group name="2D Plotting: Tasks">
            <item name="Plot Field vs. Field">
                To do 2D plotting, have at least one table open and then open a plotter
                with the <b>Tools - Plot 2D (Ctrl+P)</b> command.<br />
                <img src="images/15-plot.png" /><br /><br />

                On the plotter window, choose which table you will be plotting with and
                the rows you wish to plot.  You can then choose which fields will be used
                for the X and Y axes.  Note that only "plottable" fields can be used; for
                example, a String field could not be plotted.  For fields that contain
                array values of a fixed dimension, you can choose which "slice" of the
                array you want to plot.  Once the parameters have been chosen, there are
                two ways to plot: overplot or clear and plot.  Overplot will add the
                given plot to any pre-existing plots whereas clear and plot will clear
                any previous plots.  Note that overplotting means that all plots will be
                on the same scale, so you probably want to use similarly scaled data.
                There are also formatting options for the plot image itself.
                <br /><img src="images/16-plot.png" />
            </item><item name="Apply Row Filter">
                If there is a row filter on the table you are plotting (see
                Browsing:Tasks:Filter Rows), you have the option to apply this filter
                when plotting such that only rows that pass the filter are plotted.
                To apply the filter, check the "Apply Current Filter" box.
            </item><item name="Zooming">
                Zooming can be accomplished by selecting the "Zoom" option in the
                hand tool option box.  The region to be zoomed in on is then selected
                using the mouse on the plot canvas.  This process can be repeated to
                zoom in as far as desired.  The zoomer uses a zoom "stack" such that it
                remembers all the zoom levels and is thus able to go back and forth in
                the stack.  For example, once zoomed in you can zoom out one level
                by clicking the "Out" button or in one level by clicking the "In"
                button.  Scrolling the mouse wheel will also move out and in in the
                zoom stack.  You can return to the topmost level by clicking the
                "Base" button or by right-clicking on the canvas.  Note that these
                actions are only available when the Zoom tool is selected.  Also
                note that if another plot is added to the canvas, the zoomer is
                reset.
            </item><item name="Panning">
                Panning can be accomplished by selecting the "Pan" option in the
                hand tool option box.  The plot can then be panned by clicking
                and dragging the canvas to the desired position.  This process
                can be repeated to pan as far as desired.  To reset to the base
                position, click the "Reset" button.  Note that these actions are
                only available when the Pan tool is selected.  Also note that if
                anothe rplot is added to the canvas, the panner is reset.
            </item><item name="Selecting">
                Selecting can be accomplished by selecting the "Select" option
                in the hand tool option box.  The region to be selected is then
                slsected using the mouse on the plot canvas.  Once a region has
                been selected, the following actions may be performed on it:
                <ul> <li>Locate: generates a list of all the rows that contain
                         points in the selected region.  A window is displayed
                         containing this information with the row numbers sorted.
                         Displayed rows can then be highlighted in the browser by
                         selecting the row to highlight and then clicking the
                         "Highlight in Browser" button.  The "Next" button can
                         be repeatedly clicked to move through the displayed rows.
                </li><li>Clear: clears the selected region from the plot.
                </li></ul><h3> </h3>
                
                Note that these actions are only available when the Select tool
                is selected.  Also note that if another plot is added to the
                canvas, the selected region is cleared.
            </item><item name="Save As Image">
                To save the current plot as an image, first select the image format you
                wish to export as, then click the "Go" button.  You will be prompted to
                choose a file to save to.  If there are any problems during the export,
                an error dialog will appear; otherwise the export was successful.
            </item>
        </group>
    </category>
    
    <category name="Other">
        <group name="Tasks">
            <item name="Export to VOTable">
                To export to a VOTable XML format, use the <b>Export - VOTable</b>
                command.  You will then be able to choose the file to save to.
                Since the export process can take a while, it is possible to hide
                the progress in the background to continue using the CasaBrowser
                for other tasks.  When the export has completed, a message will be
                displayed.  If the CasaBrowser is closed while the export is still
                in progress, the behavior is undefined.  A warning will appear if
                you attempt to close the CasaBrowser during an export.
                <br /><img src="images/13-exportvotable.png" />
            </item><item name="Check Validity">
                Any test that extends a certain code interface can be used to
                check the validity of opened tables.  Currently, three tests exist
                for CASA tables:
                <ul><li><b>ID Fields are valid</b>: fields that end in <i>_ID</i>
                tend to have a special meaning in CASA tables in that they refer to
                a row in a subtable that is located in the table keywords.  (For
                example, a field called <i>ARRAY_ID</i> might refer to an
                <i>ARRAY</i> subtable.)  This test checks if fields ending in
                <i>_ID</i> have corresponding values in the table keywords.</li>
                <li><b>Subtables exist</b>: This test checks if subtables referenced
                in the table keywords exist on disk where the value says they should
                be.</li>
                <li><b>Subtables have data</b>: This test checks if subtables
                referenced in the table keywords can be opened and have at least
                one row of data in them.</li></ul><h3> </h3>
                <img src="images/14-validity.png" />
            </item><item name="Keyboard Shortcuts">
                The following keyboard shortcuts are available:
                <ul><li><b>Ctrl+O</b>: Open table.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+Shift+O</b>: Open TaQL table.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+W</b>: Close currently selected table.<br />
                        <b>Ctrl+A</b>: Close all opened tables.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+Z</b>: Undo last action.<br />
                        <b>Ctrl+Y</b>, <b>Ctrl+Shift+Z</b>: Redo last undone
                         action.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+E</b>: Enable editing mode for currently selected
                        table.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+I</b>: Show table information.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+P</b>: Open plotter.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+F</b>: Find.<br />
                        <b>F3</b>: Find next.<br />
                        <b>Shift+F3</b>: Find previous.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+Shift+F</b>: Filter on fields.<br />
                        <b>Ctrl+Shift+C</b>: Clear current filter.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+S</b>: Sort.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+H</b>: Open help.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+Q</b>: Quit.</li>
                    <li><b>Ctrl+Shift+Q</b>: Close All and Quit.</li></ul><h3> </h3>
            </item>
        </group>
    </category>
</help>
