<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>
<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
      file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">

<task type="function" name="feather" category="imaging">
	<shortdescription>Combine two images using their Fourier transforms</shortdescription>
	<description>
The algorithm converts each image to the gridded visibility plane, combines
them, and reconverts them into an combined image.  Each image must include a
well-defined beam shape (clean beam) in order for feathering to work well.  The
two images must have the same flux density normalization scale.

	</description>
	<input>
		<param type="string" name="imagename">
			<description>Name of output feathered image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="string" name="highres" mustexist="true">
			<description>Name of high resolution (interferometer) image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="string" name="lowres" mustexist="true">
			<description>Name of low resolution (single dish) image</description>
			<value></value>
		</param>
		<param type="double" name="sdfactor">
			<description>Scale factor to apply to Single Dish image</description>
			<value>1.0</value>
		</param>
		<param type="double" name="effdishdiam">
			<description>New effective SingleDish diameter to use in m </description>
			<value>-1.0</value>
		</param>
		<param type="bool" name="lowpassfiltersd">
			<description>Filter out the high spatial frequencies of the SD image</description>
			<value>False</value>
		</param>
	</input>

<example>

	Feathering is a simple method for combining two images with different 
        spatial resolution.  The processing steps are:

	       1. Regrid the low-resolution image to a temporary copy matching the
	           resolution of the high-resolution image,
               2. Transform each image to the spatial-frequency plane (gridded).
               3. Scale the low-resolution image (uv-grid) by the ratio of the
                   volumes of the two 'clean beams' (high-res/low-res). 
               4. Add to this, the uv-grid of the high-resolution image, scaled by
                   (1-wt) where 'wt' is the Fourier transform of the 'clean beam'
                   defined in the low-resolution image.
               5. Transform back to the image plane.

	Both input images must have a well-defined beam shape for this task to work. 
	This could be a 'clean beam' for interferometric images, and a 'primary-beam' 
        for a single-dish image. 

        The two images must also have the same flux density normalization scale.

	Keyword arguments:
        imagename -- Name of output feathered image
                default: none; example: imagename='orion_combined.im'
        highres -- Name of high resolution (interferometer) image
                default: none; example: highres='orion_vla.im'
	     This image is often a clean image obtained from synthesis
		observations.
        lowres -- Name of low resolution (single dish) image
                default: none; example: lowres='orion_gbt.im'
	     This image is often a image from a single-dish observations
	        or a clean image obtained from lower resolution synthesis
		observations.
         sdfactor -- value by which to scale the Single Dish image. Default is 1.0
                         Basically modifying the flux scale of the SD image
	 effdishdiam -- New effective SingleDish diameter to use in m. Obviously one can only reduce the dish effective dish diameter in feathering. Default -1.0 means leave as is.
	 lowpassfiltersd -- If True the high spatial frequency in the SD image is rejected. 
                                   Any data outside the maximum uv distance that the SD 
                                   has illuminated  is filtered out.


        Comments:

        This task can be used as one method of combining single-dish and 
        interferometric images after they have been separately made.
        
        The clean task allows another method of combining single-dish and
        interferometric data. The single-dish image can be used as a starting 
        model for the interferometric image-reconstruction. If there is
        some overlap between the spatial-frequencies contained in the 
        single-dish image and the interferometer sampling function, then,
        such a starting model will help constrain the solutions on the 
        short-baselines of the interferometric data.
        

</example>
</task>
</casaxml>
