<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>

<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">


<!-- This is the image smoothing task                         -->
<!-- step 1: construct region with the region manger tool, rg               -->
<!-- step 2: do the subtraction, with ia.continuumsub (image analysis tool) -->
<!--                                                                        -->
<!-- TODO: Add support for tophat kernels                                   -->
<!--       Add support for user defined kernels                             -->
<!--       Add support for altering the position angle for the kernel       -->

<task type="function" name="imsmooth" category="analysis">
<shortdescription>Smooth an image or portion of an image</shortdescription>

<description>
</description>

<input>
    <param type="string" name="imagename" kind="image" mustexist="true" >
    	<description>Name of the input image. Must be specified.</description>
    	<value></value>
    </param>

    <param type="string" name="kernel">
        <description>Type of kernel to use: gaussian or boxcar.</description>
        <value>gauss</value>
    </param>

    <param type="any" name="major">
	<description>Major axis for the kernels. Standard quantity representation. Must be specified for kernel="boxcar". Example: "4arcsec".</description>
 	<any type='variant' limittype='string int float record'/>
    	<value type="string"/>
    </param>

    <param type="any" name="minor">
	<description>Minor axis. Standard quantity representation. Must be specified for kernel="boxcar". Example: "2arcsec".</description>
 	<any type='variant' limittype='string int float record'/>
    	<value type="string"/>
    </param>

    <param type="any" name="pa">
	<description>Position angle used only for gaussian kernel. Standard quantity representation. Example: "40deg".</description>
 	<any type='variant' limittype='string int float record'/>
    	<value type="string"/>
    </param>

    <param type="bool" name="targetres" subparam="yes">
        <description>If gaussian kernel, specified parameters are to be resolution of output image (True) or parameters of gaussian to convolve with input image (False).</description>
        <!--
            from a usability point of view I'd say the default value should be True,
            but it has to be False for backwards compatibility
        -->

        <value type="bool">False</value>
    </param>

    <param type="any" name="region">
        <description>Region selection. See help par.region. Empty string means use box/chans/stokes if supplied, or else entire image.</description>
	<any type='variant' limittype='string stringArray'/>
        <value type='string'/>
    </param>

    <param type="string" name="box">
        <description>Rectangular region specification in directional plane. Do not specify region if you specify box.</description>
        <value></value>
    </param>

    <param type="string" name="chans" >
	<description>Select the spectral channel range. See "help par.chans" for examples. Do not specify region if you specify chans.</description>
    	<value></value>
    </param>

    <param type="string" name="stokes">
	    <description>Stokes parameters to image (eg, I,IV,IQU,IQUV). Do not specify region if you specify stokes.</description>
	    <value></value>
    </param>

    <param type="string" name="mask">
	    <description>Mask to use. See help par.mask. Default is none.</description>
	    <value/>
    </param>


    <param type="string" name="outfile" >
	    <description>Output image name. Must be specified.</description>
	<value/>
    </param>
    <param type="bool" direction="in" name="stretch" subparam="true">
        <description>Stretch the mask if necessary and possible? See help par.stretch </description>
        <value>False</value>
    </param>
    <param type="bool"  name="overwrite">
        <description>Overwrite (unprompted) pre-existing output file?</description>
        <value>False</value>
    </param>
    <param type="any" name="beam" subparam="yes">
        <any type='variant' limittype='string record'/>
        <description>Alternate way of describing a Gaussian. If specified, must be a dictionary with keys "major", "minor", and "pa" (or "positionangle"). Do not specify beam if specifying major, minor, and pa. Example: Example: {"major": "5arcsec", "minor": "2arcsec", "pa": "20deg"}.</description>
        <value type="string"/>
     </param>
     
    <constraints>
        <when param="kernel">
            <equals value="gauss">
                <default param="beam"><value type="string"></value></default>
                
                <!--
                    from a usability point of view I'd say the default value should be True,
                    but it has to be False for backwards compatibility
                -->
		        <default param="targetres"><value type="bool">False</value></default>
	        </equals>
            <equals value="gaussian">
                <default param="beam"><value type="string"></value></default>
                
                <!--
                    from a usability point of view I'd say the default value should be True,
                    but it has to be False for backwards compatibility
                -->
		        <default param="targetres"><value type="bool">False</value></default>
	        </equals>
	    </when>
        <when param="mask">
            <notequals type="string" value="">
                <default param="stretch"><value type="bool">False</value></default>
            </notequals>
        </when>
    </constraints>
</input>
<returns type="any"/>

<example>
This task performs a Fourier-based convolution to 'smooth' the
image. Smoothing is typically performed in order to reduce the noise in
an image.

Keyword arguments:
	
imagename    Input image name. Must be specified.
outfile      Output smoothed image file name. Must be specified.
kernel       Type of kernel to use when smoothing (gaussian or boxcar).
             For boxcar smoothing, the major axis is parallel to the y-axis of the image
             and the minor axis is parallel to the x-axis. For a Gaussian, the
             orientation is specified by a position angle. A value of 0 degrees means
             the major axis is parallel to the y-axis and an increasing value of the
             position angle results in a counter-clockwise rotation of the ellipse.
                default: 'gauss'; example: kernel='gauss'
                options: 'gauss' or 'boxcar' 
major        Major axis of kernel which must be specified for boxcar smoothing. For
             Gaussian smoothing, the kernel parameters can alternatively be specified
             in the beam parameter. Standard quantity representations are supported.
             Example "4arcsec".
minor        Minor axis of kernel which must be specified for boxcar smoothing. For
             Gaussian smoothing, the kernel parameters can alternatively be specified
             in the beam parameter. Standard quantity representations are supported.
             Example "3arcsec".
pa           Position angle to use for gaussian kernel, unused for boxcar. 
             The Gaussian kernel parameters can alternatively be specified
             in the beam parameter. Standard quantity representations are supported.
             Example "40deg".
beam         Record specifying Gaussian beam parameters. Do not specify any of
             major, minor, or pa if you choose to specify this parameter.
             Example: {"major": "5arcsec", "minor": "2arcsec", "pa": "20deg"}
targetres    Boolean used only for gaussian kernels. If True, kernel parameters (major/minor/pa
             or beam) are the resolution of the output image. If false, a gaussian
             with these parameters is convolved with the input image to produce
             the output image.
mask         Mask to use. See help par.mask. Default is none.
region       Region selection in the input image. See help par.region for details.
             You may specify none or one of region or a box/chans/stokes combination, but not both.
            
box          A rectangular region on the directional plane. Four comma seperated non-negative numbers,
             the first two representing the blc and the last two representing the trc, in pixels.
             The specified corners must be located within the image. Empty string means use the
             full directional plane.
             Example: "5, 10, 100, 200".
             
chans        Channel selection. See help par.chans for details.
             See "help par.chans" for examples. Empty string means use all channels.
stokes       Stokes selection. Empty string means use all stokes.
             Example: 'I'
             Options: 'I','Q','U','V','RR','RL','LR','LL','XX','YX','XY','YY', ... 



GAUSSIAN KERNEL

Major and minor are the full width at half maximum  (FWHM) of the Gaussian. pa is the position angle
of the Gaussian. The beam parameter offers an alternate way of describing the convolving Gaussian.
If used, neither major, minor, nor pa can be specified. The beam parameter must have exactly three
fields: "major", "minor", and "pa" (or "positionangle"). This is the record format for the output
of ia.restoringbeam(). For example

beam = {"major": "5arcsec", "minor": "2arcsec", "pa": "20deg"}

If both beam and any of major, minor, and/or pa is specified for a Gaussian kernel,
an exception will be thrown.    

In addition, the targetres parameter indicates if the specified Gaussian is to be the
resolution of the final image (True) or if it is to be used to convolve the input image.
If True, the input image must have a restoring beam. Use imhead() or ia.restoringbeam()
to check for its existence. If the image has multiple beams and targetres=True,
all planes in the image will be convolved so that the resulting resolution is that
specified by the kernel parameters. If the image has multiple beams and targetres=False,
each plane will be convolved with a Gaussian specified by beam (and hence, in
general, the output image will also have multiple beams that vary with spectral channel
and/or polarization).

BOXCAR KERNEL

major is length of the box along the y-axis and minor is length of the box along the x-axis.
pa is not used and beam should not be specified. The value of targetres is not used.

IN GENERAL

The major, minor, and pa parameters can be specified in one of three ways
   Quantity -- for example major=qa.quantity(1, 'arcsec')
               Note that you can use pixel units, such as 
               major=qa.quantity(1, 'pix')
   String -- for example minor='1pix' or major='0.5arcsec'
             (i.e. a string that the Quanta quantity function accepts).
   Numeric -- for example major=10.
              In this case, the units of major and minor are assumed to 
              be in arcsec and units of pa are assumed to be degrees. 

Note: Using pixel units allows you to convolve axes with different units.

EXAMPLES

# smoothing with a gaussian kernel 20arseconds by 10 arseconds
imsmooth( imagename='my.image', kernel='gauss', major='20arcsec', minor='10arcsec', pa="0deg")

# the same as before, just a different way of specifying the kernel parameters
mybeam = {'major': '20arcsec', 'minor': '10arcsec', 'pa': '0deg'}
imsmooth( imagename='my.image', kernel='gauss', beam=mybeam)

# Smoothing using pixel coordinates and a boxcar kernel.
imsmooth( imagename='new.image', major='20pix', minor='10pix', kernel='boxcar')

</example>

</task>

</casaxml>
