<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>
<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
      file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">

<task type="function" name="initweights" category="calibration">
	<shortdescription>Initializes weight information in the MS</shortdescription>

<input>
	<param type="string" name="vis" mustexist="true">
		<description>Name of input visibility file (MS)</description>
		<value></value>
	</param>
	<param type="string" name="wtmode">
		<description>Initialization mode</description>
		<value>nyq</value>
                <allowed kind="enum">
                       <value>nyq</value>
                       <value>sigma</value>
                       <value>weight</value>
                       <value>ones</value>
                       <value>delwtsp</value>
                       <value>delsigsp</value>
                </allowed>
	</param>
	<param type="bool" name="dowtsp">
		<description>Initialize the WEIGHT_SPECTRUM column.</description>
		<value>False</value>
	</param>
	</input>
<returns type="void"/>

<example>

      This task provides for initialization of the weight information
      in the MS.  For ALMA and EVLA data, it should not generally be
      necessary to use this task, as the weight information should 
      have been initialized properly at fill time (v4.2.2 and later).

      Several initialization modes are supported via the wtmode parameter.

      If wtmode='nyq' (the default), SIGMA and WEIGHT will be
      initialized according to bandwidth and integration time.  This
      is the theoretically correct mode for raw normalized visibilities.
      (e.g., ALMA).  For the EVLA, this is correct if switched-power
      and bandpass calibration will later be applied.  

      If wtmode='sigma', WEIGHT will be initialized according to the
      existing SIGMA column.  

      If mode='weight', WEIGHT_SPECTRUM will be initialized according
      to the existing WEIGHT column; dowtspec=T must be specified in
      this case.
 
      If wtmode='ones', SIGMA and WEIGHT will be initialized with 1.0,
      globally.  This is a traditional means of initializing weight
      information, and is adequate when the integration time and 
      bandwidth are uniform. It is not recommended for modern
      instruments (ALMA, EVLA), where variety in observational setups
      is common, and properly initialized and calibrated weights
      will be used for imaging sensitivity estimates.

      For the above wtmodes, if dowtspec=T (or if the WEIGHT_SPECTRUM
      column already exists), the WEIGHT_SPECTRUM column will be
      initialized (uniformly in channel), in a manner consistent with
      the disposition of the WEIGHT column.  If the WEIGHT_SPECTRUM 
      column does not exist, dowtsp=T will force its creation.
      Use of the WEIGHT_SPECTRUM column is only meaningful
      for ALMA data which will be calibrated with channelized
      Tsys information, or if the weights will become channelized
      after calibration, e.g., via averaging over time- and 
      channel-dependent flagging.  (A task for channel-dependent
      weight estimation from the data itself is also currently under
      development).

      Two additional modes are available for managing the spectral
      weight info columns; these should be used with extreme care: If
      wtmode='delwtsp', the WEIGHT_SPECTRUM column will be deleted (if
      it exists).  If wtmode='delsigsp', the SIGMA_SPECTRUM column
      will be deleted (if it exists).  Note that creation of
      SIGMA_SPECTRUM is not supported via this method.

      Note that this task does not support any prior selection.  
      Intialization of the weight information must currently be done 
      globally or not at all.  This is to maintain consistency.

 </example>
 </task>
 </casaxml>
